YERALD SALAZAR ELIZONDO

Web Developer

+3 years of experience as Web Developer. Interested in acquiring more knowledge about Software Development and staying current in a continuously growing industry. Team worker who enjoys collaborative interaction and taking advantage of the skills of each member to solve complex problems and implement front-end and back-end services that can deliver exceptional customer experience. Focused and flexible engineer to multitask when necessary.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer at BCard

Feb 2021- Present [Cartago, Costa Rica] [E-Commerce, B2B]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Turn UI & UX mock-up to a fully functional web application using Angular, JavaScript Framework, including
 a responsive design that allows the optimal operation of the system regardless of the resolution of the
 device
- Fix application/system problems or any incident that is disrupting the application Frontend service that business users depend on.
- Ensure compliance with accessibility principles and correct operation of assistive technology (Screen Reader, Screen Magnification, etc.) to obtain an inclusive and accessible software.
- Being part of a SCRUM team in an agile environment to maintain brand consistency throughout the
 development process, so a balance between functional, aesthetic design and customer interaction can be
 stroked.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- User experience improvement in mobile devices through the approach of Web Metrics refinement, applying a development with a Mobile-first approach and different optimizations for smaller resolutions.
- Reduction of the bugs number generated in the system by 15% through different debugging techniques with JavaScript, proper error handling and a mindset of experimentation and attention to detail.
- Improved frontend and backend teams cohesion and interaction, by following agile development techniques such as Pair Programming and Peer Review, as well as constant and effective communication between both.

Freelance Web Developer at MyVAccesorios

July 2020- Nov 2020 [Cartago, Costa Rica] [Handmade Accessories Marketplace, B2C]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Taking software requirements according to the company needs, in addition to the implementation of an agile methodology for the constant review and feedback of the requirements.
- Develop web application using JavaScript, CSS and HTML for the visualization and promotion of the product catalog and business social media.
- Implementation of the backend service through NodeJS with the creation of a REST API using ExpressJS for the guery of product information.
- Implementation of a non-relational database system through a data modeling and schema design for a MongoDB database in order to store product information.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Increased business sales by 10% by implementing a detailed catalog on the web of the products offered by the company.
- Improved business recognition, this was reflected in the increase of around 15% in followers on social media; accomplished by applying SEO strategies on the page for better positioning in web search engines (e.g., Google Search).

Mobile Development building StrongerMe App

Dec 2019- Sep 2020 [Cartago, Costa Rica] [Fitness App, Subscription Based Business]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Analysis and definition of software requirements according to the niche of the mobile application, and a deep understanding of a target audience.
- Development of the mobile application based on the Flutter SDK and the connection to the Firebase cloud platform for the backend service and data storage administration.
- Conceptual design and implementation of SQLite database, taking into account efficient use of local memory on mobile devices.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Broader understanding of how responsive design varies depending on device size and how it is implemented from mobile to desktop browser.
- Learning and implementation of a BaaS (backend as a service) architecture with the use of the Firebase platform backend service.
- Learning of key terms regarding the design around the accessibility of mobile applications and overall user experience.

SKILLS

- ✓ Team Player
- ✓ Research Abilities
- ✓ Problem Solver
- ✓ Fast Learner
- ✓ Methodologies: Scrum, Agile.
- ✓ SOLID Principles

- ✓ JavaScript
- ✓ TypeScript
- ✓ HTML/CSS
- ✓ Angular 2+
- ✓ TDD and BDD
- ✓ Object Oriented Programming (OOP)

- ✓ JIRA
- ✓ SQL
- ✓ MongoDB
- ✓ Flutter
- ✓ Git (GitHub)
- ✓ Basic Knowledge: NodeJS, ExpressJS

EDUCATION

Computer Engineering at Tecnológico de Costa Rica

January 2018 - Present [Cartago, Costa Rica]

LANGUAGES

Spanish, and English.